var quiz = {
    "JS": [
   
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "When crips mission came in India?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1946",
    "b": "1942",
    "c": "1909",
    "d": "1930",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1942",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Jansher Khan was the player of which game?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Polo",
    "b": "Hockey",
    "c": "Squash",
    "d": "Cricket",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Squash",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "I wish I ....rich?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "was",
    "b": "would be",
    "c": "were",
    "d": "Shall be",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "werey",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "When Indus river water treaty signed?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1961",
    "b": "1970",
    "c": "1960",
    "d": "1955",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1960",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "When Qilba was changed?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "4 AH",
    "b": "2 AH",
    "c": "6 AH",
    "d": "8 AH",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "2 AH",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "How many muslim soldiers in the battle of Badr?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "10000",
    "b": "313",
    "c": "1000",
    "d": "70",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "313",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Roohullah is the title of which prophet?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Hazrat Musa",
    "b": "Hazrat Ibrahim",
    "c": "Hazrat Isa",
    "d": "Hazrat Ismail",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Hazrat Isa",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Where is the military alliance of NATO?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Tokyo",
    "b": "Torronto",
    "c": "Vienece",
    "d": "Brussels",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Brussels",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Abu Jahal was killed in which battle?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Badr",
    "b": "Yarmuk",
    "c": "Uhad",
    "d": "Tabuk",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Badr",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The land of rising Sun is....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "USA",
    "b": "Switzerland",
    "c": "Japan",
    "d": "India",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Japan",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Where Iran is the side of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "East",
    "b": "South East",
    "c": "South West",
    "d": "West",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "South West",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "FSB is the secret agency of which country?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "UK",
    "b": "Russia",
    "c": "USA",
    "d": "Israel",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Russia",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Porto Novo is the capital city of which country?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Benin",
    "b": "Vietnam",
    "c": "Uganda",
    "d": "Egypt",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Benin",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Khyber was conquered in which year?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "6 AH",
    "b": "4 AH",
    "c": "5 AH",
    "d": "7 AH",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "7 AH",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What come next in the following series A C F....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "J",
    "b": "H",
    "c": "I",
    "d": "L",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "J",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Alter?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Different",
    "b": "Change",
    "c": "Silent",
    "d": "Waste",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Change",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "What is the 2nd largest religion of the world?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Christianity",
    "b": "Islam",
    "c": "Athiest",
    "d": "Jewish",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Islam",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "The battle of Tabuk faught in which year?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "10 AH",
    "b": "9 AH",
    "c": "6 AH",
    "d": "7 AH",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "9 AH",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which mosque build by prophet firstly?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Nabwi",
    "b": "Quba",
    "c": "Ayesha",
    "d": "None of the above",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Quba",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which country introduced the olympics game?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Japan",
    "b": "Brazil",
    "c": "Greece",
    "d": "USA",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Greece",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "When first democracy introduced in the world?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "507 BC",
    "b": "506 BC",
    "c": "504 BC",
    "d": "407 BC",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "507 BC",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "He.... early in the morning?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "woke up",
    "b": "will wake up",
    "c": "woked up",
    "d": "wake up",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "wake up",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "How many daughter's have holy prophet(PBUH)?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "4",
    "b": "5",
    "c": "6",
    "d": "3",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "4",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "If 2nd day of the month is Sunday, what will be the 26th day?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Sunday",
    "b": "Saturday",
    "c": "Monday",
    "d": "friday",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Monday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "How many muslim soldiers in the battle of Ahzab?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "3000",
    "b": "1000",
    "c": "313",
    "d": "10000",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "3000",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the capital city of Zombio?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Uganda",
    "b": "Canberra",
    "c": "Hono Lolo",
    "d": "Lusaka",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lusaka",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "What is the capital city of Canada?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Torronto",
    "b": "Newyork",
    "c": "London",
    "d": "Ottawa",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ottawa",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "2018 Commonwealth games held in which country?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Austria",
    "b": "England",
    "c": "Japan",
    "d": "Australia",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Australia",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "How many years caliphate of hazrat Ali?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "10 years",
    "b": "5 years",
    "c": "4 years",
    "d": "3 years",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "5 years",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 66 63 57 45....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "22",
    "b": "23",
    "c": "21",
    "d": "20",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "21",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Who wrote book 'Friends not Masters'?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Sir syed Ahmed han",
    "b": "Ayub Khan",
    "c": "Zia ul Haq",
    "d": "Allama Iqbal",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ayub Khan",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Mina means?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Mountain",
    "b": "Bird",
    "c": "Elephant",
    "d": "Sacrificing peace or plateau",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Sacrificing peace or plateau",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "If 4th day of the month is Sunday, what will be the 19th?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Sunday",
    "b": "Saturday",
    "c": "Monday",
    "d": "Friday",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Monday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Which is the largest plannet of solar system?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Uranus",
    "b": "Jupiter",
    "c": "Saturn",
    "d": "Mars",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Jupiter",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Which one is different from the rest?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "AD",
    "b": "IL",
    "c": "QS",
    "d": "MP",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "QS",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Which university of Pakistan is founded before independence?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "National college of Arts",
    "b": "Nust",
    "c": "Numl University",
    "d": "Punjab University",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Punjab University",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "In which year second islamic Summit held?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1979",
    "b": "1972",
    "c": "1974",
    "d": "1973",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1974",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Which city has the largest busiest railway station in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Karachi",
    "b": "Wazirabad",
    "c": "Lahore",
    "d": "Sialkot",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lahore",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Which one is out of list?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Mare",
    "b": "Fox",
    "c": "Hen",
    "d": "Lass",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lass",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Which is the most developed city of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "lahore",
    "b": "Islamabad",
    "c": "Karachi",
    "d": "Faislabad",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Karachi",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What is the position of Pakistan in cotton growning countries?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5th",
    "b": "4th",
    "c": "1st",
    "d": "2nd",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "4th",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series A C E ...?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "F",
    "b": "J",
    "c": "G",
    "d": "H",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "G",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Toot oil and natural gas field is located in?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Punjab",
    "b": "Sindh",
    "c": "Balochistan",
    "d": "KPK",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Punjab",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Monday is to February as Friday is to?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "July",
    "b": "August",
    "c": "June",
    "d": "September",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "June",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Which is the shortest river of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Sutluj",
    "b": "Jehlum",
    "c": "Ravi",
    "d": "Chenab",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ravi",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Which constitution stated that president and prime minister must be muslims?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1962",
    "b": "1956",
    "c": "1973",
    "d": "All of these",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1973",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What is the next number in the following series 4 8 24 96...?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "408",
    "b": "440",
    "c": "556",
    "d": "480",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "480",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "What is the length of Khyber pass?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "58 Km",
    "b": "54 Km",
    "c": "53 Km",
    "d": "98 Km",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "53 Km",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "Gun is to solider as ___ is to blacksmith?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Hammer",
    "b": "Sccissor",
    "c": "Scale",
    "d": "Nail",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Hammer",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
    // -------------start-------------------
    {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "On which river Guddu, Sukkar and Kotri birrage are located?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Ravi",
    "b": "Jhelum",
    "c": "Chenab",
    "d": "Indus",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Indus",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // -----------------End-----------------
   


    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });